<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ismail Mechbal Full Stack Developer &amp; UX/UI Designer</title>
    <description>Ismail Mechbal is a passionate web developer, love to tackle difficult challenges and ride awesome waves.</description>
    <link>https://www.sboura.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sboura.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 23:04:56 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 23:04:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.5</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>10 ways to have a better conversation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/07/care-about-others.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;10 ways to have a better conversation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of endless distration, I find myself regularly ashamed of how I communicate with others, Celeste Headlee gave a great TED Talk on better conversation, I do my best to work it on, below a summary of the talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t multitask&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t pontificate. If you want to state your opinion without any opportunity for response or argument or pushback or growth, write a blog&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use open-ended questions. In this case, take a cue from journalists. Start your questions with who, what, when, where, why or how.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go with the flow. That means thoughts will come into your mind and you need to let them go out of your mind&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you don’t know, say that you don’t know&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t equate your experience with theirs. If they’re talking about having lost a family member, don’t start talking about the time you lost a family member.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try not to repeat yourself&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stay out of the weeds. Frankly, people don’t care about the years, the names, the dates, all those details that you’re struggling to come up with in your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Listen (post link to tim interview with the known interviewer)
Stephen Covey said it very beautifully. He said, “Most of us don’t listen with the intent to understand. We listen with the intent to reply.”
“If your mouth is open, you’re not learning.” And Calvin Coolidge said, “No man ever listened his way out of a job.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be brief. A good conversation is like a miniskirt; short enough to retain interest, but long enough to cover the subject. – Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/celeste_headlee_10_ways_to_have_a_better_conversation/transcript?language=en&quot;&gt;TED Talk by Celeste Headlee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/07/care-about-others.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;10 ways to have a better conversation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/10-ways-to-have-a-better-conversation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/10-ways-to-have-a-better-conversation/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the glass half full or half empty?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/07/is-the-glass-half-full-or-half-empty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Is the glass half full or half empty?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed reading this short post from Seth Godin on optimism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the glass half full or half empty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pessimist sees what&#39;s present today and can only imagine eventual decline. The glass is already half empty and it&#39;s only going to get worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optimist understands that there&#39;s a difference between today and tomorrow. The glass is half full, with room for more. The vision is based on possibility, the future tense, not the present one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pessimists have trouble making room for possibility, and thus possibility has trouble finding room for pessimists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as we realize that there is a difference between right now and what might happen next, we can move ourselves to the posture of possibility, to the self-fulfilling engine of optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image credit: HRMexplorer’s Blog – Human Resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2016/05/the-possibility-of-optimism-the-optimism-of-possibility.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/07/is-the-glass-half-full-or-half-empty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Is the glass half full or half empty?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/is-the-glass-half-full-or-half-empty/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/is-the-glass-half-full-or-half-empty/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving back to Sweden</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/07/stockholm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moving back to Sweden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is time again to switch destination and seek new adventures, this time I’m returning back to Stockholm, house of the new unicorns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will miss a lot my family and friends, I will also miss the ocean and surfing.
I will not miss a whole bunch of stuff, that I hope it will get better when I return back to Morocco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image credits: Wikimedia&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/07/stockholm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moving back to Sweden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/moving-back-to-sweden/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/moving-back-to-sweden/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Nobody wants to read your sh*t</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/06/nobody-wants-to-read-your-shit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nobody wants to read your shit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody wants to read your shit&lt;/strong&gt;, a book I highly recommend for marketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A snapshot from Chapter 4:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you understand that nobody wants to read your shit, your mind becomes powerfully concentrated. You realize that writing/reading is, above all, a transaction. The reader donates her time and attention, which are extremely valuable commodities. In return, you the writer must give her something worthy of her gift to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you understand that nobody wants to read your shit, you develop empathy. You acquire the skill that is indispensable to all artists and entrepreneurs—the ability to switch back and forth in your imagination from your own point of view as writer/painter/seller to the point of view of your reader/gallery-goer/customer. You learn to ask yourself with every phrase and every sentence: Is this interesting? Is it fun or challenging or inventive? Am I giving the reader enough? Is he bored? Is he following where I want to lead him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.blackirishbooks.com/pages/nobody-wants-to-read-your-sh-t-download&quot;&gt;Download the book while for FREE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/06/nobody-wants-to-read-your-shit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nobody wants to read your shit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/nobody-want-to-read-your-shit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/nobody-want-to-read-your-shit/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Love people and use things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What most people need to learn in life is how to love people and use things instead of using people and loving things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016/06/inspiration-tim-ferriss-love-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Love people and use things&quot; class=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is inspired from Tim Ferriss’s instagram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;What most people need to learn in life is how to love people and use things instead of using people and loving things.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/love-people-and-use-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/love-people-and-use-things/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Scientific studies shows that studies are not scientific</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific studies shows that studies are not scientific&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well you get the point, so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/U7P2vnWfPkIQ8&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;288&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://giphy.com/gifs/cheezburger-olympics-U7P2vnWfPkIQ8&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific studies shows that studies are not scientific&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/scientifc-studies-shows-that-studies-are-not-scientific/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/scientifc-studies-shows-that-studies-are-not-scientific/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Your job vs. your project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting article from Seth Godin on the importance of projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jobs are finite, specified and something we &#39;get&#39;. Doing a job makes us defensive, it limits our thinking. The goal is to do just enough, not get in trouble, meet spec. When in doubt, seek deniability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects are open-ended, chosen and ours. Working on a project opens the door to possibility. Projects are about better, about new frontiers, about making change happen. When in doubt, dare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jobs demand meetings and the key word is &#39;later&#39;. Projects encourage &#39;now.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get paid for a job (or a project). Or not. The pay isn&#39;t the point, the approach is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people don&#39;t have a project, only a job. That&#39;s a choice, and it&#39;s a shame. Some people work to turn their project into a job, getting them the worst of both. If all you&#39;ve ever had is jobs (a habit that&#39;s encouraged starting in first grade), it&#39;s difficult to see just how easy it is to transform your work into a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to projectworld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2016/06/your-job-vs-your-project.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting article from Seth Godin on the importance of projects.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/your-job-vs-your-project/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/your-job-vs-your-project/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Kelly&#39;s 14 Rules applied to software engineering</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just learned about Kelly Johnson, and how he disrupted the military aviation industry with 14 simple rules, I copied some of these rules that can be applied to software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The number of people having any connection with the project must be restricted in an almost vicious manner. Use a small number of good people (10% to 25% compared to the so-called normal systems)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A very simple drawing and drawing release system with great flexibility for making changes must be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There must be a minimum number of reports required, but important work must be recorded thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lockheedmartin.com/us/aeronautics/skunkworks/14rules.html&quot;&gt;Click on this link to read the complete 14 rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend watching this Keynote from Nickolas, where I learned about Kelly’s rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ggPE-JHzfAM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I just learned about Kelly Johnson, and how he disrupted the military aviation industry with 14 simple rules, I copied some of these rules that can be applied to software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/kelly-johnson-14-rules-applied-to-software-engineering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/kelly-johnson-14-rules-applied-to-software-engineering/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The crème de la crème!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from DHH article “We only hire the best”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best are generally the best because they aren’t typical. Because they came at things from a different angle that gave them a unique perspective, which happens to provide more insights than the widely-distributed approaches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/we-only-hire-the-best-c711c330fc2e#.e2as6n17q&quot;&gt;Read the full article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celeste Headlee said in her TED talk “10 ways to have a better conversation”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everybody is an expert in something, Everyone you will ever meet knows something you don’t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/celeste_headlee_10_ways_to_have_a_better_conversation?language=en#t-628462&quot;&gt;Watch Celeste TED talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from DHH article “We only hire the best”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/the-creme-de-la-creme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/the-creme-de-la-creme/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>My job application to Basecamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, 3rd June 2016, while listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/the-journal/jason-fried&quot;&gt;Jason’s podcast with Kevin Rose, The Journal&lt;/a&gt;, I thought holy crap, why didn’t I ever apply to Basecamp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything happens for a reason, and the reason it is I will apply today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Mercedes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason &amp;amp; David have been a great source of inspiration to me for more than 8 years. SVN, Getting Real, Rework &amp;amp; Work in progress have all helped me shape my views in design, product, programming and most importantly life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember three years ago when I had to switch from PHP and choose between Python or Ruby, I chose the latter because of Ruby on Rails and 37signals philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider myself lucky, I have a constant desire to learn, I love keeping up to date with technology as well as reading and writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been introduced to web design since my early age, I’m 33 now, I developed my first website in 1998, a phishing website, not very proud of, thankfully it was just for fun and learning purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2007, I had an opportunity to study a Master degree in Human Computer Interaction at Uppsala university, usability together with design principles that I learned from Ryan &amp;amp; Jason helped me understand what makes great products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t count how many times I listened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0CDXJ6bMkMY&quot;&gt;DHH talk at Startup School 08&lt;/a&gt;, it highly inspires me and motivates me whenever I’m working on a new product, which I tried several times and failed proudly; I’m more than confident now that a great team and a great execution is key to success, however I also learned that life is also about giving, thank you for Ruby on Rails and please contemplate on this quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What most people need to learn in life is how to love people and use things instead of using people and loving things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My satisfaction doesn’t come by excelling at one skill, I prefer to learn and use as many skills as I can by applying the 80/20 rule, therefore you might find me either UX’ing, coding, blogging, marketing, cooking, supporting customers, selling, mentoring or even surfing :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unik.ma&quot;&gt;Unik&lt;/a&gt;, a web agency where we had the pleasure to work with amazing clients from all around the world, recently I launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://werunik.com?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=basecamp_marketing_designer_job&quot;&gt;Werunik&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;“Fucking web development agency”&lt;/strong&gt; as I like to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my free time, I love sharing some stories, ideas, technical tips on my personal blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sboura.com/resume?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=basecamp_marketing_designer_job&quot;&gt;sboura.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started teaching web design to Sakina, my 8 years old daughter, here is a sample of what we’ve been baking:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sakinamechbal.github.io/&quot;&gt;http://sakinamechbal.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’m looking forward having my name and illustration on
https://basecamp.com/about/team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find my resume on the following link:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sboura.com/resume?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=basecamp_marketing_designer_job&quot;&gt;sboura.com/resume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psst: I have two secrets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I published this job application to my personal blog, on this link.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I use Nylas N1, an open source email client, I highly recommend it to keep track of email opens and clicks, by which I will take further actions based on your interaction with this email :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
Ismail Mechbal
&lt;a href=&quot;https://werunik.com?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=basecamp_marketing_designer_job&quot;&gt;werunik.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hope is not a strategy, luck is not a factor, failure is not an option” - James Cameron&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, 3rd June 2016, while listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/the-journal/jason-fried&quot;&gt;Jason’s podcast with Kevin Rose, The Journal&lt;/a&gt;, I thought holy crap, why didn’t I ever apply to Basecamp!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.sboura.com/my-job-application-to-basecamp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sboura.com/my-job-application-to-basecamp/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
